Wrege, Charles D. Research Material Publications 6395 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles D. Wrege Research Material Publications
1887-2007
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wrege, Charles D.
6395 PUBS
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Articles, reports, pamphlets, publications.
8754067
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 18, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, May 11, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Charles "Chuck" Wrege finished his undergraduate degree in Upsala College, obtained his Masters degree at the New School fo Social Research and another Masters of Business Administration and his Ph.D. at NYU. He taught industrial management at Rutgers University for 30 years. He became a renowned historian, researcher and writer. He is regarded as a "National Treasure" by many in his field because of his expertise and the seminal research he has done in the area of management history.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
8754067
- 50 Years of Education for Business (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 222 Broadway (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Academy of Management Handbook (1983) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Academy of Management Journal Vol. 17 No. 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Academy of Management Leadership Directory 2003-04 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Academy of Management News (1990) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Academy of Management Newsletter (1977-84) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Advanced Management Vol. 21 No. 4 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Alexander Hamilton Church and the Development of Modern Management - Joseph Litterer (1961) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Answers to Problems in Principles of Electrical Engineering (1922) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Around the System: Centennial of Light (1979) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bibliography of Management (1931) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Birth and Early Days of the Calculagraph (1939) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bookkeeping Under the Taylor System (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bulletin on the Engineering Department (1907) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bulletin of the National Association of Corporation Training (1921) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society Vol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society: Proceeding of the Meeting Vol. 5 No. 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society: Handbook on the Taylor Society Vol. 6 No. 1 (1921) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society Vol. 7 No. 6 (1922) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society Vol. 8 No. 1 (1923) (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society Vol. 9 No. 1 (1924) (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society: Critical Essays on Scientific Management Vol. 10 No. 1 (1925) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society Vol. 12 No. 5 (1928) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Bulletin of the Taylor Society: Methods Study Vol. 15 No. 5 (1930) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- The Business Machine (1949) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Centennial of Lights (1947) (Box 1, Folder 27)
- The Chief Cause of this and Other Depressions (1935) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- The Cincinnati Historical Society Bulletin Vol. 34 No. 2 (1976) (Box 1, Folder 29)
- The Cleveland Garment Plan (1923) (Box 1, Folder 30)
- A Collection of Original Frederick W. Taylor Documents (1978) (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Contributions of Lighting Research Laboratory (1911-48) (Box 1, Folder 32)
- The Critics of Stakhanovism (1958) (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Defense Training (1942) (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Destinations Vol. 12 No. 2 (1997) (Box 1, Folder 35)
- The Development of Electrical Technology in the 19th Century (1962) (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Discovering Some of the Roots of Taylor's "Shop Management" (Box 1, Folder 37)
- The Edison System of Electrical Lighting (1920) (Box 1, Folder 38)
- The Edison System of Incandescent Lighting from Central Statin (1887) (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Effect of Air Movement on the Individual (1947) (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Effective Management and the Behavioral Sciences (1972) (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Electrical Lighting in the First Century of Engineering (1952) (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Electric Railway Journal Transportation Department (1911) (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Elton Mayo and the Hidden Hawthorne (1987) (Box 1, Folder 44)
- The Engineer and Planning (1958) (Box 1, Folder 45)
- The Engineering Approach to the Problem of Continuous Employment (1921) (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Engineering Foundation (1925) (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Engineers' Council for Professional Development (1955) (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Factory: The Magazine of Management (1925) (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Fatigue and Efficiency (1913) (Box 1, Folder 50)
- First Iron Workers Gazette (1953) (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Frederick V. Taylor: The Future of Scientific Management Vol. 2 (1923) (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Frederick W. Taylor: The Father of Scientific Management (1991) (Box 1, Folder 53)
- The Hawthorne Experiment: First Statistical Interpretation (1978) (Box 1, Folder 54)
- The Hawthorne Studies (Box 1, Folder 55)
- How the Telephone Works (1964) (Box 1, Folder 56)
- The Howell Works Restoration (1971) (Box 1, Folder 57)
- The Human Machine in Industry (1918) (Box 1, Folder 58)
- In Transition (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Industrial Revolution of the United States (1895) (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Industrial Lighting (1921) (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Industrial Psychology (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Insider Track (2006 - Summer) (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Lecture Notes on Some of the Business Meetings on Engineering Practice (1912) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- LIGHT Magazine (1923-24) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lighting and the Nation's Welfare (1951) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lighting Journal (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lizzie Likes Her Job (1920) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The Locktender Vol. 21 No. 1 (1997) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- The Management Historian as a Detective (1977) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Management's Responsibility to Society (1957) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Management Trainee Program (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Many Unusual Features in New Types of 4-Wheel Cars (1928) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Maximum v. Minimum Hour Legislation (1917) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Method of Directing the Work of Government Employees (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mertrolink on the Move (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Midvale (1867-1942) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Midvale and its Pioneers (1948) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Muscle Action Potentials - As Related to Visual Tasks in Industry (1951) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- The N-file Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Journal of the NJ Potential History Society (2007) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- National Commercial Gas Association Proceedings (1910) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- National Commercial Gas Association Proceedings (1911) (Box 2, Folder 20)
- National Commercial Gas Association Proceedings (1913) (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Newsletter: Women in Management Division Academy on Management (1984) (Box 2, Folder 22)
- On the Problem of Organizing for the Chief Executive (1943) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- The Star Ledger (1988) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Parapsychology Bulletin (1950-52) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Part Two of the Lighting Sales Course (1924) (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Personal Relationships as a Basis of Scientific Management (1915) (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Personal Relationships in Business Administration (1916) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- A Price-Rate System (1895) (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Planning Department as an Instrument of Executive Control (1923) (Box 2, Folder 30)
- The Present State of Industrial Management (1912) (Box 2, Folder 31)
- The Problem of the Manager Forum (1928) (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Proceedings of the American Gas Institute Index to Vol. 1-10 (1916) (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Public Service Review: 25 Years of Public Service (1928) (Box 2, Folder 34)
- The Quantitative Measurement of Human Efficiency Under Factory Conditions (1930) (Box 2, Folder 35)
- A Report on the Taylor System of Scientific Shop Measurement (1914) (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Scientific Measurement and its Relation to the Health of the Worker (1916) (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Scientific Management in Churches (Box 2, Folder 38)
- "Search for Schmidt" (1976) (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Smoothing the Wrinkles from Management (1928) (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Snapping Cords (1915) (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Social Research Inc. (Box 2, Folder 42)
- The Spirit of Scientific Management (1917) (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Spring Labor Historical Society Newsletter (2007) (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Statistical Compilation (1922) (Box 2, Folder 45)
- A Study in Historical Efficiency (Box 2, Folder 46)
- The Story of Boxly (2007) (Box 2, Folder 47)
- The Story of Nickle Plating (1959) (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Sunshine and Cloudiness at Selected Stations in the United States (1951) (Box 2, Folder 49)
- TILCA (Box 2, Folder 50)
- The Taylor Key Award (1945) (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Telephone Power Manual (1939) (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Teletype: Description and Amendments of Brush Type Distributors (1928) (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Teletype (1930) (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Time-Study and Task Work (1913) (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Trolley Talk (1985) (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Utilities Research Commission (1929) (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Western Electric Human Relations Program (1949-53) (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Winner Company (1979) (Box 2, Folder 59)
- What Can Science do About Psychic Experiences (1951) (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Women in Management Newsletter (1991) (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Work on the Employment and Service Department of the \ Shops (Box 2, Folder 62)